Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
- Boré, Jean Etienne, 1741-1820. A.L.s.(translation) to [ ]; New Orleans, 25 Feb 1799., 1s.(4p.)
- Borghese, Pauline (Bonaparte), princess, 1780-1825. A.L.s. (Pauline) to Lucien [Bonaparte?] La Fovorita, 22 Sep 1814., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-499(14). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Borghese, Pauline (Bonaparte) princess, 1780-1825. A.D.s.; Paris, 6 Aug 1813., 1s.(1p.)
  Receipt.
  *42M-1371. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Borghi Mamo, Adelaide, b. 1829. A.L.s. to [Fernando Palka]; Lisbon, 30 Mar 1866., 1s.(1p.)
  Palka autographs, 4655, n.d.
- Borne, Ludwig, 1786-1837. A.L.(facsimile, unsigned) to Auguste Wohl; Frankfurt, 17 Sep 1818., 1s.(1p.)
- Bornet, M. A.L.s.to D. Croker; [n.p.] 27 Nov [18-?], 1s.(3p.)
- Bornier, Henri, vicomte de, 1825-1901. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 6 Apr 1898., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (44). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Borrow, George, 1803-1881. A.L.s.to J. Sparham; Dutton Lowestoft, 29 Jan 1843., 1s.(4p.)
  Also engraved photograph with signature.
- Borrow, George, 1803-1881. A.L.s. to Roger Kerrison; Norwich, 20 Jan 1824., 1s.(3p.)
  *56M-44. Purchased with the Bemis fund from Myers Co., Ltd., Oct 1956.
- Borrow, George, 1803-1881.; Conrad Wallinrod. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(3p.)
  Poem translated from the Polish of Adam Mickiewicz.
  *59M-58. Purchased with the Bemis fund from Goodspeed's Book Shop, Oct 1959.
- Borrow, George, 1803-1881. [Fragment concerning Man, Mona, and other islands] A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., 187-?], 1s.(2p.)
  In Borrow's later hand.
  *44M-318. Purchased from Elkin Mathews, Sotheby Sale, 3 Feb 1945.
- Bosanquet, Charles Bertie Pulleine, 1834-1905. A.L.s. to [Elizabeth Cleghorn (Stevenson)] Gaskell; Scarborough, 14 Jun [186-?], 1s.(4p.)
  Recat. fr. bMS Am 1088.
  Norton family, n.d.
- Boscawen, Edward, 1711-1761. MS.D.s.; aboard H.M.S. Namur, Louisbourg Harbor, 29 Aug 1758., 1s. (1p.)
  Gift of Elijah Clark, 28 July 1844.
- Boscawen, Edward, 1711-1761. MS.D. (contemporary copy); H. M. S. Alamur, in Gabreuse Bay, 25 Jul 1758., 1s. (1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. M. A. Potter, 1 July 1930.
- Bossuet, Jacques Bénigne, bp. of Meaux, 1627-1704. A.L. (unsigned) to his uncle [ ]; Rome, 23 Sep 1698., 5s.(20p.)
  *45M-181(57) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bossuet, Jacques Bénigne, bp. of Meaux, 1627-1704. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  Excerpts from the fathers of the church.
  In Latin.
  *45M-181(58). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bossuet, Jacques Bénigne, bp. of Meaux, 1627-1704.
  Facsimiles.
- Boston. MS.L.s. (James Bowdoin,; Saml. Pemberton,; Joseph Warren) to Sir George Saville [i.e., Savile]; Boston, 23 Mar 1770., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-1240F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Boston. City council. MS.D.s. (W.S.McCleary, city clerk); Boston, 4 Jul 1836., 1s.(1p.)
  Copy of a resolution thanking Henry Willis Kinsman for his oration delivered 4 Jul 1836.
  *48M-326. Kinsman Papers. Presented by Mrs. Gamaliel Bradford, 27 May 1942.
- Boston journal of natural history. D.s. (Ch. K. Dillaway); Boston, Dec 1839., 1s.(1p.)
  Receipt to Thaddeus William Harris for subscription.
  *47M-373 (132). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Boston. Public library. D.s.( John P. Bigelow ); Boston, 20 Apr 1858., 1s.(1p.)
  Acknowledgement of a gift of books from Mrs. J. Putnam Bradlee.
  *42M-1941 (21). Presented by the Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Boston. Selectmen. MS.D.s.(6 signatures); Boston, 14 Sep 1757., 1s.(2p.)
  Order to pay widow of James Hamilton the wages not paid him before his death.
  *47M-373 (12). From the estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Boston. Selectmen. Excerpts from minutes of town meetings 1641-1684: manuscript document transcript?, 1828?, 1s.(4p.)
  Pencilled note: Gannett May 31, 1828. Probably removed from larger collection, page stamped: 1255.
- Boswell, Sir Alexander, bart., 1775-1822. A.L.s.to Robert Lang; Grafton Street, 7 Jul 1817., 1s.(2p.)
- Boswell, James, 1740-1795. A.L.s. to [Thomas Percy]; [London] 13 Apr [1776], 1s.(1p.)
  Harold Murdock collection, n.d.
- Boswell, James, 1740-1795. A.L.s. to Henry Thrale; Edinburgh, 13 May 1774., 2s.(3p.)
- Botta, Anne Charlotte (Lynch), 1815-1891. A.L.s. to Fitz-Greene Halleck; New York, 23 Nov 1864., 1s.(4p.)
- Böttiger, Carl August, 1760-1835. 2 A.L.s.to Anna Brownell (Murphy) Jameson:
  - [Weimar] 13 Nov [18–], 1s.(1p.)
  - [Same] 14 Nov [18–], 1s.(1p.)
- Bottomley, Gordon, 1874- A.L.s. to [ ]; Carnforth, 15 Apr 1933., 1s. (4p.)
  About the composition of The acts of St. Peter.
  *63M-138. Purchased with the Duplicate fund, Jan 1964.
- Botts, John Minor, 1802-1869. A.L.s.to C. A. Davison; Washington, 25 Jan 1842., 1s.(1p.)
- Bouchet, Alfred-Leon. 3 letters to Paul Pelliot;1943.
  Gift of J. Buttinger, 1973.
- Bouck, William C, 1786-1859. Document s.; Albany, 27 Mar 1846., 1s.(1p.)
- Boudinot, Elias, 1740-1821. A.L.s. to Jonathan Dayton; Rosehill, 25 Oct 1804., 1s.(3p.)
- Boufflers, Stanislas, marquis de, 1738-1815. [Ode au retour de Louis XVIII] A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., 1814], 1s.(2p)
  *49M-187 (45). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Boughton, George Henry, 1834-1905. A.L.s. to Thomas Bailey Aldrich; [London, 2- Jan 1879], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1133. Presented by Talbot Aldrich, Esq., 7 June 1943.
- Boughton, George Henry, 1833-1905. Letters to [ ] Andrews:
  - A.L.s.; Whitchurch, 28 Jul 1895., 1s.(4p.)
  - A.L.s.; Felixstowe, 2 Oct 1895., 1s.(4p.)
    *53M-133. Received gratis, May 1954.
- Boughton, George Henry, 1833-1905. A.L.s.to John Durand; Kensington, 23 Mar 1876., 1s.(2p.) env.
- Boughton, George Henry, 1834-1905. A.L.s. to James Thomas Fields; Kensington, 7 Jul 1875., 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-181(59). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Boulez, Pierre, 1925- 2 letters to John Milton Ward;1962-1963.
  *79M-27. Gift of Prof. John M. Ward, 19 May 1980.
- Bourget, Paul, 1852-1935. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  With photographic portrait of Bourget.
  *42M-1278F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bourget, Paul, 1852-1935. A.L.s. to [ ]; [Oxford, n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (46). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bourget, Paul, 1852-1935. A.L.s. to [Robert Louis Stevenson]; Londres [i.e. London] 3 Aug 1893., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-156. Purchased with the Morris Gray fund from Austin Strong, 15 Oct 1942.
- Boulliau, Ismaël, 1605-1694. A.L.s. to Stanislaw Lubieniecki; Paris, 5 Dec 1664., 1s.(3p.)
  *77M-15 (2). Purchased with the Degrand fund, 27 July 1977.
- Bouquet, Henry, 1719-1765. A.L.s.to Richard Peters; Fort Pitt, 22 Oct 1761., 1s.( 3p.)
- Bourdillon, Francis William, 1852-1921. To Matthew Arnold, in America. A.MS.s.; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1414. Gift of Talbot Aldrich, 7 June 1943.
- Bourn, Melatiah. A.L.s.to Col. John Stevens; Boston, 29 Nov 1762., 1s.(2p.)
- Bourne, Benjamin, 1755-1808. A.L.s.to Mrs Bourne; Philadelphia, 2 Mar 1796., 1s.(1p.)
- Bourne, William Sturges, 1769-1845. A.L.s.to Thomas Joseph Pettigrew; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Bourneville, Désiré Magloire, 1840-1909. A.L.s.to [ ]; Paris, 11 Aug 1873., 1s.(1p.)
- Boutroux, Émile, 1845-1921. 7 A.L.s. (photocopies) to Marcel Jay;1917-1918 and [n.d.].
  Concerning Jay's translations of Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.
  With 2 A.L.s. by Marcel Jay to [K] [I] Jamieson; 1961.
  Gift of Miss K.I. Jamieson, 3 Mar 1972.
- Boutroux, Emile, 1845-1921. A.L.s. to J. Perreau; Paris, 26 Jul 1901., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *49M-187 (47). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s.to F. S. Brooks; Boston, 27 Dec 1863., 1s.(2p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s.to Albert Bushnell Hart; Boston, 22 Dec 1899., 1s.(1p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s.to [ ] Pollock; Washington, 29 Apr 1873., 1s.(1p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. Document, s.; Washington, 17 Apr 1872., 1s.(1p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A. signature; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s. to William Stevens Robinson; Washington, 24 Jul 1866., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1943. Presented by the Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s. to [Edward Forbes] Waters; [Washington] 25 Mar 1871., 1s.(4p.)
- Boutwell, George Sewall, 1818-1905. A.L.s. to William D. Sohier; Groton, 23 Apr 1896., 6s.(6p.)
  *45M-181 (96) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bouvé, Pauline Carrington (Rust). A.L.s.to Florence (Cushman) Milner; Boston, 6 Feb 1924., 1s.(2p.)
  Gift of Mrs. Florence Milner, 29 Apr 1924.
- Bowditch, Henry Ingersoll, 1808-1892. A.L.s.to Charles Frances Adams; [Boston?] 8 May 1869., 1s.(3p.)
- Bowditch, Henry Ingersoll, 1808-1892. A.L.s.to [Miss ] Channing; Milton Hill, 27 Feb 1870., 1s. (4p.)
- Bowditch, Henry Ingersoll, 1808-1892. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 2 May 1879., 1s.(2p.)
  *47M-373 (13) From the estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Bowditch, Nathaniel Ingersoll, 1805-1861. A.L.s.to James Thomas Fields; Boston, 2 Aug 1858., 1s.(1p.) env.
- Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838. A.L.s.to Theodore Lyman; Salem, 21 Mar 1820., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838. A.L.s. to Ichabod Nichols; Salem, 12 Oct 1807., 1s.(4p.)
- Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838. Document, s.; [n.p.] 8 Oct 1828., 1s.(1.p.)
- Bowditch, Vincent Yardley. A.L.s.to Francis Weld Peabody; Boston, 5 Jun 1909., 1s.(4p.)
  Removed from US 13568.3(IIC).
- Bowdoin, James, 1726-1790. A.L.s. to [ ] Darby; Watertown, 24 Oct 1776., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-499(15) Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Bowdoin, James, 1726-1790. A.L.s. to Jasper Mauduit; Boston, 2 Nov 1762., 1s.(3p.)
  in duplicate.
  Enc. is an attested copy, s. by Andrew Eliot, of a vote of thanks passed for friendship to the college.
  *52M-39. Presented by Henry S. Grew, purchased with the Ellis fund from Maggs Brothers, 11 July 1952.
- Bowen, Clarence Winthrop, 1852- A.L.s.to Richard Salter Storrs; [New York] 24 Dec 1892., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowen, Francis, 1811-1890. A.L.s.to Houghton company; [n.p.] [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bowen, Francis, 1811-1890. A.L.s.to Edwin Percy Whipple; Cambridge, 23 Jan 1844., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowen, Francis, 1811-1890. A.L.s.to [ ]; [Cambridge] 1 Dec 1859., 1s.(1p.)
  *59M-205. Gift of Jerry E. Patterson, Jan 1960.
- Bower, B. Autograph manuscript letter (signed) to his parents (Elijah Bower); Rochester, New York, 1826 August., 1s.(3p.)
  Give description of factories in Rochester and farming.
- Bowers, T. S. A.L.s.to Adam Badeau; Nashville, 5 Nov 1863., 1s.(1p.) env.
  Bowers was Gen.U.S.Grant 's aide.
- Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878. A.L.s. (Initials) to Charles [Allen]; Edinburgh, 15 Aug [1871], 1s.(4p.) env.
  *45M-181(63) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878. A.L.s. (initials) to Charles [Allen]; Springfield, 13 Sep 1876., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(64) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bowles, Samuel, 1826-1878. A.L.s.to William Leonard Gage; New York, 20 Jan 1862., 1s.(4p.)
  Gift of C. H. Taylor, 1924.
- Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850. A.L. to [ ] Hunt; Bath, 1 Dec 1823., 1s.(2p.)
  Cut fragment.
  Removed from *83-331.
- Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
  Removed from F55.44.
- Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850. Lines written at Weston Super Mare August 5th [1832.] A.L.s.; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(2p.)
  Removed from *83-338-40.
- Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850. On the marriage of Miss Parker. A.MS.s.; Clifton, 20-25 Jul 1836., 1s.(3p.)
- Bowra, C. M. (Cecil Maurice), 1898-1971. Letter to John Livingston Lowes, ca. 1930 November 10., 1s.(1p.)
  Removed from a (discarded) copy of Bowra's Tradition and design in the Iliad, 1930.
  2010M-26. Purchased from the library of John Livingston Lowes, 1945 December 13.
- Bowring, Deborah (Castle) Lady. A.L.s.to [ ]; Somerset, 3 Oct 1873., 1s.(4p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to Maria (Weston) Chapman; London, 8 Sep 1842., 1s.(3p.)
  Includes A.MS. poem: The Liberty Bell.
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to [Athanase Laurent Charles] Coquerel; [n.p.] 18 Feb 1833., 1s.(2p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to Daniel O'Connell; London, 22 Oct 1860., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to Professor [ ] Phillips; [n.p.] 28 Feb 1826., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to Henry Crabb Robinson; [n.p.] 11 May 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London] 25 Mar 1828., 1s.(1p.)
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s. to [ ]; Exeter, 10 Oct 1870., 1s.(3p.)
  Includes: A. Poem s. in 8 stanzas; Liverpool, Sept 1870. (2p.)
  *45M-181(65) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bowring, Sir John, 1792-1872. A.L.s. to [ ]; Exeter, 20 Oct 1871., 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-181(66). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Boycott, Charles Cunningham, 1832-1897. A.signature; Battinrobe, Co. Mayo, 14 Jan 1882.
  His name is the origin of the word "boycott".
- Boyd, Andrew. A.L.s.to C. S. Taft; New York, 25 Mar 1867., 1s.(3p.)
- Boyd, Andrew Kennedy Hutchison, 1825-1899. A.L.s. to [ ]; Edinburgh, 31 May 1861., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(67) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Boyd, Andrew Kennedy Hutchison, 1825-1899. 3 A.L.s.to James T. Fields:
  - Edinburgh, 1 May 1863., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 14 Oct [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  - St. Andrews, [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Boyd, Andrew Kennedy Hutchison, 1825-1899. A.L.s.to Ticknor Fields; Edinburgh, 14 Dec 1860., 2s.(5p.)
- Boyd, Madeleine (Reynier) T.L.s. to [Henry Seidel] Canby; New York, 8 Jan 1936., 1s.(1p.)
  Enclosed is transcription of the inscription by Thomas Wolfe in Mrs. Boyd's copy of Look homeward, angel!
  *42M-496. Purchased with the Bemis fund from Richard S. Wormser, 17 Mar 1943.
- Boyd, Thomas, 1867- 2 letters to David James O'Donoghue:
  - T.L.s.; London, 23 Nov 1905., (1); 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; same, 27 Jan 1906., (2); 1s. (1p.)
    *42M-732 and 733. Purchased with the Gray fund from Richard G. Wormer, 19 Apr 1943.
- Boyesen, Hjalmar Hjorth, 1848-1895. A.L.s. to Frank W. Hoyt; Paris, 25 Mar 1879., 1s.(1p.)
  Recat. fr. X 5.11 F*.
  Gift of Norton Perkins, 11 Nov 1925.
- Boyesen, Hjalmar Hjorth, 1848-1895. A.L.s.to J. B. Lippincott Co.; New York, 16 May 1892., 2s.(3p.)
  Including corrected proof of biographical note with additions.
- Boyle, Mary Louisa, 1819-1890. T.L.s.to [Mrs James Thomas] Fields; Killarney, 22 Jan [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Boyle, Kay, 1903- 2 A.L.s. to Polly Papkee; [n.p.]. 29 Nov 1964., 2s.(4p.)
  Recat. fr. *AC9. B6975.944a.
- Boyle, Kay, 1903- A.L.s. to Edward Douglas Papkee; [n.p.] 6 Dec 1964., 1s.(2p.) env.
  Recat. fr. *77-960.
- Boynton, Henry Van Ness, 1835-1905. A.L.s.to Ben. W. Austin; Washington, 7 Apr 1887., 2s.(2p.)
  Includes signed photograph and clipping.
- Brackett, Anna Callender, 1836-1911. A.L.s.to Ben. W. Austin; New York, 3 Dec 1892., 1s.(1p.)
- Brackett, John Quincy Adams, 1842-1918. A.L.s. to William Barrett; Boston, 7 Apr 1894., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1945. Presented by the estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843. A.L.s.to [ ]; Boston, 25 Oct [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843. A.L.s.to Dwight Foster; [Boston] 19 Jun 1818., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradford, Alden, 1765-1843. MS.L.s.to Ezra Starkwether; [Boston] 5 Dec 1820., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradford, Edward Hickling, 1848-1926. A.L.s. to [Annie (Adams)] Fields; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(3p.)
  *50M-410. Transferred from the Boston Medical Library, 11 Apr 1951.
- Bradford, Ephraim Putnam, 1776-1845. A.L.s.to Lemuel Shaw; West Springfield, 16 Feb 1804., 1s.(3p.)
- Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932. T.L.s. to [Miss ] Milner; Wellesley Hills, 31 Mar 1924., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932. T.L.s.to A. C. Potter; Wellesley Hills, 28 Jun 1931., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradford, Charles Frederic. MS.L.s.to James Russell Lowell; Roxbury, 11 Nov [1883?], 1s. (4p.) env.
  Estate of Mrs. A. Kingsley Porter, 1963.
- Bradford, Gamaliel, 1862-1932. 25 letters to Marvin Sprague;1923-1931.
  No. 24 is incomplete.
  Gift of Priscilla C. Sprague, 22 Oct 1974.
- Bradford, Samuel, 1759-1818. A.L.s.to Ezra Starkweather; Boston, 20 Sep 1800., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradish, Isaac. [Itemized bill for costs of running the Cambridge jail from Aug 1761 to Aug 1762]. A.MS.s.; Cambridge, 8 Sep 1762., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-338F. Purchased with the Sheldon fund from F. G. Sweet, 12 Apr 1946.
- Bradish, P.P. A.L.s. to [ ] Griswold; Batavia, 19 May 1909., 3s. (3p.)
  *45M-655. Anonymous donor, 1944?
- Bradlee, Caleb Davis, 1831-1897. A.L.s. to [ ]; Boston, 19 Jun 1884., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradley, Arthur Granville, 1850- A.L.s. to Charles Gordonsmith; Rye, 21 Feb 1926., 2s. (4p.) env.
  *46M-157. Gift of Dr. W. I. Morse, 4 Jan 1947.
- Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889. A.L.s. to [ ]; Peterborough, 14 Oct 1869., 1s.(4p.)
- Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889. A.L.s. (Cuthbert Bede, pseud.) to Richard Bentley Son; Grantham, 27 Sep 1888., 1s.(4p.)
  Gift of D. B. Fearing, 30 June 1915.
- Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889. The lady and the spaniels... A.MS.s. (Cuthbert Bede); Stilton, Peterboro [n.d.], 3s.(3p.)
  With pencil drawing.
  Accompanied by A.L.s. to [ ]; Stilton, Peterboro, 9 Dec [ ] 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1253F - 1255F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- [Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889] Autograph signature (Cuthbert Bede [pseud.]); [n.p.] 1863.
  With photograph of Bradley.
  *42M-1256F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- [Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889] Autograph signature (Cuthbert Bede [pseud.]) On envelope addressed to A. Vogue; [postmark: Peterborough, 8 Dec 1863]
  With *42M-1253F-1255F. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- [Bradley, Edward, 1827-1889] A.s. (Cuthbert Bede) on env. addressed to Charles Welsh; [Oakham, Rutland, 29 Apr 1880]
  *42M-784. Presented by W. B. O. Field, 23 May 1943.
- Bradley, George P. A.L.s.to W. B. Clarke; Portland, 11 Jul 1891., 1s.(1p.)
- Bradley, Will, 1868- T.L.s. to Albert Eugene Gallatin; South Pasadena, Cal., 2 Dec 1948., 1s.(1p.) env.
  Concerns Bradley's printing of The happy hypocrite, by Sir Max Beerbohm.
  *48M-149. Gift of A.E.Gallatin, Esq., 17 Jan 1949.
- Bradley, Will, 1868- T.L.s. to Herbert Kleist; Short Hills, 11 Jan 1956., 1s. (1p.) env.
  *62M-251. Gift of H. Kleist, 14 May 1963.
- Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1878-1939. A.L.s.to Thomas Wentworth Higginson; New York, 13 Jun 1904., 1s.(4p.)
- Bradshaw, Henry, 1831-1886. A.L.s.to Benjamin Perley Poore; Cambridge, England, 7 Oct 1871., 1s.(2p.)
- Bradstreet, John, 1711-1774. A.signature on fragment of letter to John Tabor Kempe; [n.p.,n.d.]
- Bradstreet, Simon, 1603-1697. A.signature; [n.p.] 1667.
- Bradstreet, Simon, 1603-1697. A.D.s.; Hingham, 6 Jul 1683., 1s.(1p.)
- Brady, John R. A.L.s.to Adam Badeau; [n.p.] 3 Dec 1887., 1s.(1p.)
- Brady, [Mathew B., 1823 (ca.)-1896?], photographer.; Jane Slidell Perry: portrait photograph, [n.p., n.d.]., 1 item
  Jane Slidell Perry was Mrs. Matthew Calbraith Perry.
  *93M-293. No source or date.
- Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876. MS.L.(copy) to [Jefferson Davis]; Richmond, 19 May 1864., 1s.(4p.)
  Gift of R.W. Foster, n.d.
- Brahe, Tycho, 1546-1601, subject. Notes on Tycho Brahe: manuscript; no place, undated., 1 folder.
- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. A.L.s. to Ernst Frank; [n.p.] Aug 1871., 1s.(4p.)
  *49M-58. Presented by Dr. William Inglis Morse, 16 Dec 1949.
- Brainard, John Gardiner Calkins, 1796-1828. The falls of Niagara. A.MS.s.; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1878- A.L.s.to Madison Cawein; New York, 1 Apr 1912., 1s.(2p.) env.
- Bramlette, Thomas E A. signature; n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Branch, Stephen H. The dying confession of Stephen H. Branch. A.MS.s.; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brandard, Robert, 1805-1862. A.L.s.to William Bernard Cooke; Sussex, 23 Sep 1833., 1s.(1p.)
- Brandard, Robert, 1805-1862. A.L.s.to Henry Magford; Kensington, [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brandes, Georg, 1842-1927. 5 A.L.s. to [Dr. ]; Copenhagen,1906-1907.
  See Accessions Records, 1955-56, under *55M-6. Purchased with the Benis fund from Herbert Steiner, July 1955.
- Brandes, Georg,1843-1927. A.L.s. to [Hedwig ?] Heller; Copenhagen, [1 Jan ] 1926., 1s.(2p.)
  *44M-45. Gift of Clemens Heller, 29 July 1944.
- Branford, Victor, 1864- A.L.s.to [E Howard]; New York, 19 Jul 1908., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. Gaspar Bacon, 1941.
- Brassey, Annie (Allnutt) Brassey, baroness, 1839-1887. A.L.s.to [General ] Badeau; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Brassey, Thomas Brassey, 1st earl, 1836-1918. A.L.s.to [ ]; New York, 13 May 1905., 1s.(1p.)
- Brassey, Thomas Brassey, 1st earl, 1836-1918. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London, n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Brassey, Thomas Brassey, 1st earl, 1836-1918. A.L.s.to [Field?]; [London] 29 Jun 1871., 1s.(1p.)
- Brattle, William, 1663?-1717. A.L.s. to John Cotton; Cambridge, 16 Jul 1687., 1s.(2p.)
  Notes by Victor H. Paltsits on Cotton and Brattle.
  *51M-235. Presented by Harold T.White, purchased from Victor H. Paltsits, 23 May 1952.
- Brattle, J. A.L.s.to Benjamin Bourne; Cambridge, 30 May 1792., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. Bella C. Landauer, 1939.
- [Bray, John, 1782-1822] MS.(unidentified hands]; [n.p., n.d.]., 2s.(2p.)
  *67M-76 (3). Gift of Roger E. Stoddard, 1 July 1967.
- Bray, John, 1782-1822. A.MS.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(2p.)
  List of payments by the manager of the New York Theatre for certain compositions by Bray.
  *67M-76 (1). Gift of Roger E. Stoddard, 1 July 1967.
- Bray, John 1782-1822. [Who pays the piper: cast list] A.MS.S.; [n.p., 1813?], 1s.(2p.)
  *67M-76 (2). Gift of Roger E. Stoddard, 1 July 1967.
- Bray, William, 1736-1832. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 6 Feb 1817., 1s.(1p.)
- Braybrooke, John Griffin, 1st baron, 1719-1797. MS.L.(3d person) to [ ] Leader; Audly End, 17 Dec 1797., 1s.(1p.)
- Braybrooke, Richard Neville Griffin, 3rd baron, 1783-1849. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 29 Sep [n.d.]., 1s.(4p.)
  *64M-235. Purchased with the Duplicate fund, 7 Jun 1965.
- Brayley, Edward Wedlake, 1773-1854. A.L.s.to [ ] Booth; [n.p.] [Aug 1816], 1s.(1p.)
- Brazer, John, 1787-1846. A.L.s.to Thomas Jefferson; Cambridge, 15 Jul 1819., 1s.(2p.)
  Gift of W.K. Bixby, 1913.
- Brearley, David, 1745-1790. 2 A.L.s.to [Hendrick Wilson ]:
  - Trenton, 5 Dec 1783., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 5 Apr 1786., 1s.(1p.)
- Breck, Samuel, 1771-1862. MS.L.(3d person) to Dwight Foster; [n.p.] 7 Feb 1798., 1s.(1p.)
- Breckinridge, Henry, 1886- Typed L.s. to William G. McAdoo; Washington, 13 Aug 1913., 1s.(1p.)
  Includes: Typed L.(W. G. McAdoo) to Col. E. M. House; [n.p.] 15 Aug 1913.
  *45M-181(69). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Breckinridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. A.L.s.to Alonzo A. Hamilton; Washington, 29 Dec 1857., 1s.(1p.)
- Breckenridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. MS.L. (copy) to Robert Edward Lee; Richmond, 28 Apr 1864., 1s.(2p.)
- Breckinridge, John Cabell, 1821-1875. A.signature; [n.p.,n.d.]
- Breckinridge, Robert Jefferson, 1800-1871. A.L.s. to A. C. Robbins; 22 Apr 1844., 1s.(2p.)
- Breese, Ima Gale 2 A.L.s.to [ ] Estabrook:
  - Springfield, 7 Dec 1930., 3s.(3p.)
  - New York, 3 Feb 1933., 1s.(1p.)
    Gift of Alford Franklin Benoit, 1940.
- Bréguet, Antoine. A.L.s. to E Dueretet; Paris, 24 Oct 1878., 1s.(1p.)
  *52M-177. Purchased from E. Weil, 6 Feb 1953.
- Bréguet, Antoine. A.L.s. to [E ] Dueretet; Paris, 5 Apr 1882., 1s.(1p.)
  *52M-178. Purchased from E. Weil, 6 Feb 1953.
- Bréguet, Louis. A.L.s. to [ ] Jullien; [Paris] 23 Oct 1823., 2s.(8p.)
  Notes on Abraham Louis Bréguet enclosed.
  *52M-176. Purchased from E. Weil, 6 Feb 1953.